<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on CURIOSS</title><link>https://curioss.org/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on CURIOSS</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://curioss.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>10 quick tips for making your software outlive your job</title><link>https://curioss.org/news/10_quick_tips/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curioss.org/news/10_quick_tips/</guid><description>&lt;p>A new preprint, &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.06484">10 quick tips for making your software outlive your job&lt;/a>, offers essential guidance for researchers and developers concerned with the longevity of their software projects. The paper addresses a pervasive challenge in academic and research environments: how to ensure valuable software tools remain functional and accessible after their original creators move on to new positions or projects. The guide is particularly timely as shifts in funding and organizational priorities are potentially impacting the continuity of valuable software resources.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Academic Open Source Workshop at CHAOSSCon Europe 2025</title><link>https://curioss.org/news/2025-02-27-academic-open-source-workshop-chaosscon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curioss.org/news/2025-02-27-academic-open-source-workshop-chaosscon/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="1-introduction">1. Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://chaoss.community/chaosscon-2025-eu">CHAOSScon Europe 2025&lt;/a>, co-located with &lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2025">FOSDEM&lt;/a>, took place in Brussels, Belgium, on January 30, 2025. As part of the conference, &lt;a href="https://curioss.org">CURIOSS&lt;/a> sponsored and facilitated a dedicated discussion on academic open source. The workshop brought together researchers, software developers, and open source advocates to discuss the challenges and opportunities of sustaining open source software in academia. With 12 participants in attendance, the discussions were divided into two sessions. The first session focused on understanding different types of research software, their sustainability, and institutional support. The second session expanded on these topics, addressing funding uncertainties, emergency open sourcing, and legal considerations related to intellectual property.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Academic-Industry Collaboration</title><link>https://curioss.org/news/nov24-industry-partnerships/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curioss.org/news/nov24-industry-partnerships/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-ospos-support-academic-industry-partnerships">How OSPOs Support Academic-Industry Partnerships&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>At a recent panel discussion at the Linux Foundation Open Source Summit Europe 2024, titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/HhlQajqwGYU?feature=shared">Collaboration with Universities and Enterprises: OSPO - What&amp;rsquo;s Next?&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;, TODO Group members and CURIOSS members shared insights on bridging the gap between academia and industry through Open Source Program Offices (OSPOs).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Academic OSPO Definition</title><link>https://curioss.org/news/academic_ospo_defn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curioss.org/news/academic_ospo_defn/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the last 20 years, Open Source Program Offices (OSPOs) have become a relatively common feature in major tech companies and other industries. Many businesses rely upon their OSPOs to manage open source software efforts within their organizations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Licensing Resources for Academic OSPOs</title><link>https://curioss.org/news/licensing_resources_for_academic-_ospos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curioss.org/news/licensing_resources_for_academic-_ospos/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://curioss.org/resources/">CURIOSS Community Resources&lt;/a> spreadsheet lists all the resources referenced by our members in calls and activities. It provides a handy guide to relevant resources created by both CURIOSS members and other individuals and organizations in the academic open source ecosystem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Funding awarded to support the growth of CURIOSS</title><link>https://curioss.org/news/new_grant_supports_development_of_curioss/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curioss.org/news/new_grant_supports_development_of_curioss/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://sloan.org/">Alfred P. Sloan Foundation&lt;/a> has awarded funding to Clare Dillon and Richard Littauer to develop and expand the work of CURIOSS, the community for university and research institution OSPOs, over the next three years. The award comes after an initial grant from the Sloan Foundation to establish the CURIOSS network in 2023.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New CURIOSS members</title><link>https://curioss.org/news/six_new_members/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curioss.org/news/six_new_members/</guid><description>&lt;p>CURIOSS is delighted to welcome six new University Open Source Program Offices (OSPOs) to the CURIOSS network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Funding awarded for CURIOSS Network</title><link>https://curioss.org/news/funding_awarded_for_curioss_network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://curioss.org/news/funding_awarded_for_curioss_network/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://sloan.org/">Alfred P. Sloan Foundation&lt;/a> has awarded a one-year grant to coordinate a set of community-centered activities focused on university-based and research institution Open Source Program Offices (OSPOs).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>